Every war has a beginning.
Underworld: Rise of the Lycans is a fantasy, action,
thriller film directed by Patrick Tatopoulos.
A prequel to the first two Underworld films, this fantasy explains the
origins of the feud between the Vampires and the Lycans.
Aided by his secret love, Sonja, courageous Lucian leads the
Lycans in battle against brutal Vampire king Viktor.
Determined to break the king's enslavement of his people, Lucian faces off
against the Death Dealer army in a bid for Lycan independence.
Sonja, played by Rhona Mitra.
Viktor, played by Bill Nighy.
Lucian, played by Michael Sheen.
Kraven, played by Shane Brolly.
Andreas Tanis, played by Steven Mackintosh.
Raze, played by Kevin Grevioux.
Underworld: Rise of the Lycans is a 2009 American action horror film directed by Patrick Tatopoulos from a screenplay by
Danny McBride, Dirk Blackman, Howard McCain, based on a story by Len Wiseman, Robert Orr, and McBride.
It is a prequel to Underworld (2003) and the third
installment in the Underworld film series.
The film stars Michael Sheen, Bill Nighy, Rhona Mitra,
Steven Mackintosh, and Kevin Grevioux.
The plot focuses primarily on the origins of the characters and
the events that lead up to the Vampire–Lycan war.
Kate Beckinsale, who starred in the previous Underworld
films, appears briefly at the end of the film.
Underworld: Rise of the Lycans premiered at the ArcLight Hollywood in Los Angeles, California on January
22, 2009, and was released in the United States on January 23, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and grossed over
$91 million against its production budget of $35 million.
The film was followed by Underworld: Awakening, in 2012, serving as
a direct sequel to Underworld: Evolution (2006).
The film explores themes of prison, vampire, slavery, castle, forbidden love.
The tone is dark and intense.